hey everybody Welcome to the three
question series with the alliance I'm
here with Kathy
jeny and Rachel stevener and we are GNA
do three questions today but first just
introduce yourselves so they know who's
who tell us who you are okay wel go uh
my name is Kathy jeny and I am the
director of women's ministry and
congregational Care at Grace
Presbyterian Church of Silicon Valley in
California we're near San Francisco so
and I'm Rachel stevener I am a Ministry
partner um at Grace PR helping Kathy
with women's
ministry yeah and a little bit about our
jobs um so there we didn't have a
women's ministry when I was first hired
on staff and so spent the last five and
a half years um you know following God
to establish a Ministry to the women in
our church um and you know that includes
things like Bible study
and um some trainings and um just
equipping our women to um care for one
another that's really important to us um
the congregational care piece is um care
in our congregation both men and women I
work with the session I work with our
pastors um on just a variety of things
um abuse situations I'll be involved
with um just to be able to have a female
perspective which has been really really
helpful and support you know especially
when it's like domestic abuse in a in a
marriage um but even just long-term
chronic care Crisis Care we work
together that we should say that you
have your degree in
counseling yes okay so yeah I have I
have I have a degree from Westminster um
Theological Seminary in biblical
counseling so that has helped immensely
with with this Ro
sure and your Sidekick here my side um I
have such a sweet job it's I get to
taste a little bit of everything without
the full-time aspect um so I get to help
with Communications and kind of
articulating our vision and Ministry um
on our emails and through a Ministry we
have called stories of Grace it helps
women write Faith Reflections monthly
that we share with other women in the
church um I get to help Shepherd our
women's ministry team which are our
Bible study leaders
and also help with Bible study
curriculum as needed um my other little
Corners are my home my four girls my Ruf
campus Minister husband and um a singer
songwriter writes I write music so yeah
and I would say my other little Corners
I'm a grandmother to two spirited little
boys and um three adult children and
then also biblical counseling I I do
that um as part of a practice as a and
as an intern and I I want to say How
Sweet It Is for Rachel and I to work
together there is just this
um I don't know this unity and there's
not a competition she I am so weak she
is so strong and I'm so grateful for
that and we just we work together and
God has blessed that and and it and it's
given me confidence to try some new
things and just to have to bounce it off
of Rachel and I we've really seen God
flourish the ministry because of us
working together um with a broader you
know idea and vision than what I have
yeah one thing about um women's ministry
our our vision for this ministry is to
unfold women into the life of the church
so we're really not siloed over on its
own as women's ministry our goal is
always how do women become part of the
church to really undergird our Church's
mission of gather grow and go so we're
always thinking about that does this fit
in with that mission of our church how
do we support the mission of our church
um I love that it's such a great
ministry model the two of you working
together there's a church here in St
Louis that has the same thing and the
you're so the two of you are so
different but you work so well together
like what a great ministry model you
know to have the two of you working
together okay so those are your little
corners of the Kingdom here's my next
question I would love to hear a story
tell us a story of God at work in your
ministry they're looking at their notes
I'm I'm gonna give them a second yeah no
that's okay thank you because it's like
just one there's so many I bet yes yes
but one of I the things that I has been
very exciting especially that we've seen
in the last year actually two things but
um they kind of go together we've just
seen women um ministering to one another
and that's something that we have prayed
for um and have encouraged our women's
ministry team by doing some trainings we
read through Ed Welch's Side by side um
and that really equipped our Bible study
leaders and our women's ministry team to
kind of take that model of we are needy
and needed how do we care for one
another how do we pray not just
circumstantial prayers and they they've
done that into their groups and now
we're seeing the fruit of that where
women really are caring for one another
in ways that um we hadn't seen before I
think the other thing is when I first
started this job five years ago I would
hear from women quite often saying I
just don't believe belong here I don't
belong because I don't have a PhD I
don't belong because I'm not married I
don't belong because I don't have kids
or my kids have special needs or what
there was just this list I not heard
that in quite a long time um and Rachel
and I were talking we think part of that
is just in the way that we've been
supported and encouraged is taking um
the ministry philosophy of our church
and looking at what do we do and keeping
our focus on
Jesus on the
gospel and again an infolding women into
the life of the church so they do belong
because they belong to Jesus and that is
taking root so it's cool yeah I think um
yeah another part of our vision is to I
mean you said it already but basically
encouraging women in one anothering and
really the whole congregation um I think
the fact that that's our Church's
posture gives us courage to to follow
that too you know to carry that out um
and the way like she said that that God
is working and making women care for
other women it means that it's not all
on us and you know biblical counseling
degree I have a degree from RTS
Charlotte and biblical studies like
we've got some some things to trickle
down and give but like the lifeblood of
the church being the church to one
another in Christ is what will carry it
further it's not about us you know right
so there's not so encouraging you're
like helping them to use their gifts not
just you're not the show yes and I don't
I think too like the beauty of of this
happening maybe stems partially from
like our our women's ministry not being
hyper programmatic it it creates like we
have Bible studies that will never
change as far as like we will always be
studying God's word and then we also
have opportunities we've created to for
women to join in Fellowship around
another activity or thing like a neutral
kind of ground creativity or activity
and um
yeah even small groups for Special Needs
Moms with special needs kids and an
abusive marriages and those grou yeah
there they're like needs that are being
met but our ministry is not needs driven
you know based on on needs like we're
not just following the next need of the
church but it's I don't know it's kind
of sweet Duality there yeah and
listening to what are women wrestling
with like we did a um oh gosh what do
you call it a panel a panel discussion
um on loneliness and in that we had you
know an older single woman we had a
woman with four children we had a woman
who who married a non-believer who did
come to Faith Midway in her marriage we
just had from different walks of life
and that was really impactful and I
think our women heard there's so many
different women and experiences and look
at what God has done and they have been
our church and we are together I think
that has added to the I belong because I
belong to Jesus and he's work and I can
talk to lots of different women even
though they look very different from me
yes encouraging yeah it is encouraging
and okay so here's my third question is
especially given the fact that you guys
are in such a unique context you're and
when she mentioned Stanford uh or she
mentioned phds they're right up next to
Stanford so um tell me
about what do you love about the PCA you
guys are sort of far removed from what I
would think of as like the center of the
PCA what have you loved about being
PCA you start yeah you start well I I
grew up in the Southeast and so
initially PCA was what I knew As I Grew
in my faith and it to me it was a family
of Faith like I felt like but that but
that family of Faith was grounded in
God's word and I found that to be true
in every PCA um church I've been in
throughout the country from east to west
um just that solid foundation on God's
word as like the fountain from which all
other things in life blow in and
Ministry and I love that I love that um
consistency that Unity that we
have and I um I did not grow up in the
church and came to Faith in Hong Kong
and um later in life and didn't begin
you know my my Christian Life in a PCA
church so then I came to it and what I
love so so much I was so hungry as I was
looking where where am I going to land
lord um that this PCA church is Gospel
centered Christ centered through and
through and we just know where we stand
and Rachel and I were talking about how
it gives us courage to be really solid
in our Bible studies and to bring God's
word in and how do we apply it how do we
chew on it how do we talk with one
another not just maybe compl complaining
about the hard things but okay well who
is God in that and how might he change
that and what does it mean Jesus died
and rose again as we're wrestling with
you know XYZ let's bring that in and
we're really supported in that and
encouraged in that and we just started a
a new study Bible study and to um to
have our pastor just be praying for our
women start this study as they are
learning more and more how to apply the
depths of God's word it's beautiful
so they are supporting you your pastors
are supporting you and tell us how we
the church the the all of the church can
be supportive to you in your roles and
maybe other women in roles like
yours
um I mean maybe I I guess remembering
again that that beauty of our unified
theology is something to celebrate and
and then also to stem off from that like
a way to grow would be to also celebrate
the diversity of our cultural context
and place and and maybe into that more
um as far as equipping from those view
viewpoints if that makes sense so like
you know recognizing California and its
cultural and geographical difference
from you know Florida that's an
important distinction it doesn't mean we
have different theology it means that we
can sensitively approach you know
Californians can be encouraged to
approach Californians in a sensitive
[Music]
women walking alongside you and your
life begins to be
rescripted in the gospel and in who
Jesus is and just hearing him recognize
that and encouraging us in our roles I
just felt so filled and I and I said you
know thank you I just love hearing so
that kind of encouragement I think too
just hearing what God is doing in other
churches is really helpful we we have a
stories of Grace that we send out once a
month where women write about life and
faith
um and that women love that it's it's
just encouraging how is God at work and
I think that's a great encouragement
again in that contextual way like how's
he work in California how is he at work
in other places yeah oh that's so good
you guys thank you thank you for being
willing to talk to me and whoever else
about just what's going on give us a
picture into what you do every day and
thank you for your work there we really
appreciate it thank you all right
yay